Please sit comfortably and after
we begin please do not move
[music] there
will be a long meditation so again
everything is really comfortable we will
do an imitation which is called this is a
very good meditation for the beginning of the day
this meditation is from the master asanga
who founded the school only so here we
go you can record this meditation
if you want
and so
please with your face I know
[music] [music] [music
]
[music]
shoulders relaxed
we have at the collector
so for a
few minutes 20 conformation
let's focus on this sounds
larch
please do not move do not make
any sounds
[music]
now alone
it is enough to feel
the elevator so leave the external condensation
and go inside and obedience your heart
and around the
heart please if you need to
cough try to hold back [
music]
over time you can learn to hold back
porridge
[music]
let's move super quietly
much quieter
[music]
This is made of classic beautiful
wood, very, very beautiful league
[music]
[music] there is a
small one on the table, it is worth saving
and I open the lid and with the finger of my left hand and
[music] I
lower this finger, it is saved, I
pulled out one
sugar crystal, it remains on my finger, and I choose one
single border and I think I would
like to place my mind inside this
sugar crystal, the
window again,
it is as if I want to open a
small door inside this
sugar crystal and go there, 12 head through
the foreign currency and penetrate inside this, it is a
sugar crystal and I put it
inside and closes the door of this
sugar crystal, open the door and go
inside, small-small, when
I get inside, the space again
becomes very comfortable for
meditation, a lot of sunlight in the blog,
very convenient,
quiet, online and spacious
or tanka for free, so place
your mind in this tiny point and
[music]
stay inside, sugar crystals, but
inside the temple it does not feel cramped,
exit from there, it is very spacious and comfortable,
let me imagine the entire Pacific Ocean,
the ship itself installed disks that
covers almost half of this planet and
[music]
I place this entire Pacific Ocean inside a
sugar crystal,
thousands of kilometers of ocean, and very quiet,
very blue, deep ocean, and all
this inside a sugar crystal, that moment,
and this is mine, he will catch, is that, or coffee,
my mind is the Pacific Ocean, and m to the bottom, behind the
skin,
I am very deep
inside one sugar crystal
[music]
Now, please imagine
not an ocean of liquid inside a
sugar crystal, and it will create a very vast
Pacific Ocean, fruits, Ufa, and above the ocean,
Sabirov, Obninsk, a beautiful blue sky
formed,
covering this entire ocean, goes very,
very high,
insiders, red, and so inside a
sugar crystal, and dry, like Ufa, us
everywhere, our own, the
enormous ocean, how big, how the
world weighs, above the ocean, the deepest sky
stretches to the edges of the ocean, low,
reaches the greatest heights, in the soul, you
simply, and all this inside a sugar crystal,
let's go deep now, we would like, wanted,
even more of these, we must,
more calmly, like a light, our mind
is aware of many things, thinks about many
things, is aware of many things, Igor, or
astronomers, in the fog, and what if we are simply
turned off, just like we turn off the light  In
the room I count to three and when I say
three, turn off the room on mine and after that there
should be no thoughts with you
with the stone
if you hear any thoughts arise
in your mind or images think over then you are
writing in general and therefore he you
quantity let's have it around
Nastya and the last step is the master
reducing you are baptized waters but we will go
deeper and what happened with the fireplace they now
if thoughts arise they can and
think in pieces if any images
arise just ignore my mind
visa on Modena my thoughts are not my
images
my quiet it is turned off just ignore
these things potentially stay in
perfect silence us the last part of the
meditation
and focus on your breathing with 3
long exhalations
no need slowly open your eyes and
[music]
drink something well done it was
very quiet except that there was climbing
on something you are great my youth do you
want more or want to stop
[music]
if you need to go to the toilet go and
that's normal here is the closet and but
come back quietly
[music]
body chapter
and killer cough and so let's continue
[music]
please sit up straight close your eyes and
start observing your breathing
[music]
long-long when you reach
the end of the exhalation exhale a little
more long exhalations
and at the end take another small
inhalation automatically so there you go 10
long exhalations
try to be quiet and not move
if you want to cough try to
control malefice minox mouth
relaxed face relaxed and
[music]
now I want you to think about one
of your teachers could be your eyelids
teachers mom and dad it could be your
favorite teacher from school it could
be a spiritual teacher it could
be someone who learned your profession in
Cuba at what is different fist it
could be one of the great teachers of
history Confucius Jesus or Muhammad
any great number and ask the teacher
please come I'll meditate with me come on let's
sit for a month on twitter
come on  meditating together and the teacher
comes very very happy to come with you
[music]
do not think that this is an image of the teacher,
this is a real teacher, a real living one and
yours are very happy that your eyes are
closed, your teacher's eyes are open and
he or she looks at you with great
love and great pride that you are
meditating,
you can even feel the warmth of the body, feel a
pleasant aroma, it's your
turn and you meditate together and
make this image real
[music]
for which your teacher especially loves
very very calmly, can help or
your teacher, or maybe loves to help
sick people, or your teacher and never get
angry and always calm,
choose one quality that you love
in your teacher,
I see this quality, the
teacher himself orders, thanks to which
what I did in the past, maybe in
my past life I was a very
patient person or I liked
helping the elderly or I liked
helping sick people, free of fame,
so let's have fun, Danish
side grew up and let's dive into
our past life test, we are alone,
just in our imagination we cannot
see directly our past lives and
congress, but we can guess what we
did, oh, it
must be, I was very  a patient
person or should I have
helped other people a lot we can guess
what kind of personality we had what country
we lived and what we looked like
8 topics what kind of job I had
how many hundreds of years ago I lived when I
was patient am I men or women maybe
I even was a bird or a fish and
Canadians then we can't see this
directly
pasture we can
put maybe I was such
men or even women in another country
[music]
all you can imagine a
sample of genocide where you have seeds for this
if you have seeds for this
maybe this is a little true so
enjoyed goats create a canon of your
past life puppies let your
imagination run wild this meditation will not
be very long smoke and fire of the state of traffic
rules and then we will stop for today
so relax be patient
and enjoy write this story of
your past life were a very good
person or sowed these wonderful
seeds new but for me it's a very long
drive please go back to your
teacher
catch up look at your teacher
[music]
so I am now  I see my teacher from
my past life I helped many
people I worked hard and other people I
was very calm if it arises very
kind to other people and thanks to this
I now have a wonderful teacher
there are good seeds and we will take three
deep breaths exhale all the air
out and so
slowly open your eyes
[music]
these teams market
ask any questions raise your hand
general the rest of all questions we
will answer tonight now any
questions about meditation we have a
microphone hello gish but I have a
question about
I feel sleepy and have a
headache when I focus on
meditation and it doesn't matter what time I did
meditation I always want to sleep quietly
the more it is directed I focus
from the thickness the more the main thing is to
feel more questions how to overcome this
problem and how to develop passion for meditation
[music]
if your headache increases
hands start shaking and is it
right there is a very simple way
to fix
two things can be done but there was the first
[music]
during meditation the exhalation should be
very long not to when you
exhale exhale very  A long exhalation
and then a natural pause in
breathing occurs and after that, an exhalation begins, an inhalation,
you exhale, then a pause,
and then an inhalation begins. 15 years usually
all people have three parts of breathing: an exhalation
and an inhalation. The
son of a turbine has been around since you were a
child. This is a natural way of breathing.
When you meditate,
you need to release a little more air
when you reach the end of the
exhalation and pause. Exhale a little more
air. There is always a little
air left in the lungs and during meditation,
this residual air in the lungs
accumulates in black
breathing. This is not about anything, but breathing is
connected with whose prana.
Therefore, if too much air
remains in the lungs and or about it
increases, accumulates, what
symptom can appear in you? Chest pain and
you may begin to feel
nervous, maybe your hands will start to ache, and a
special kind of headache means a
dry headache. I don't know why they
call it that, but it feels like this. A
headache means too much chili. This
can be fixed very easily. Just
exhale a little extra
air when you meditate.
If you are too serious, you need to
stop. Stop doing
meditation for a few days and it also
helps.  eat heavy food, fatty food,
lots of protein and no sugar,
no coffee,
no tea, then what calms down,
then you can start
meditating again, it is important to do something about the fact
that you have a headache
because otherwise it can harm you,
so you need to immediately start doing this
special breathing,
eat healthier food, more protein,
more oily fatty food,
dark green vegetables and this will help, then
you will feel better
during meditation and your hunger, your passion
for meditation will increase. Today
we did a long meditation
because we all came to Bali and
we have a good chance to meditate
together here, but usually my suggestion is to start
meditating 10 minutes a day,
do not meditate more than ten minutes,
do 10 minutes this week and
every week increase, every
Sunday add one minute, no one
ever follows the teacher's advice,
you will try to meditate for one
hour and you will not succeed and you will stop
meditating, so my advice is 10 minutes
starting from today, just start with 10
minutes
and enjoy. 10 minutes with good
focus is much better than an hour with bad
focus.  focus becomes
a habit
so this week please please please please please
10 minutes next week
Sunday
increase to 11 next week
increase to 12 when you don't stop
meditating you will enjoy
meditation and then time will pass
quickly and in a year and in fifty-two
weeks you will meditate for 1 hour and that's
perfect that's great please don't
try don't try to meditate for 1
hour this week we meditate for so
long in a group because you came to
Bali you need to try very hard
here but when you get home
do only 10 minutes
then you were you were you will
enjoy meditation and I see I
asked my teacher and when I don't
really feel like meditating or it seems like
it's not very not the most fun what should
I do very strange I'll tell you
what you can do before watch people
around you die I received mail this morning
we have a good friend in Sedona you
know her name is Viola her father suddenly
got serious cancer and most likely we will be
red within two weeks
why do you meditate the
goal is not that you would feel
more  happy is not the main goal, the
circle is trying
to incense, which means we are trying to kill
death, the only way to kill death
is to see emptiness directly, this is the
only way to see emptiness
directly, 1 hour of good meditation
every day for a year, start with 10 minutes,
we do not meditate for fun,
we do not meditate just to become
quiet and calm,
if you cannot meditate for one hour, you will
not be able to see the statue, and if you do not
see emptiness directly, you will die and
people around you will like this kind of
motivation, meditation is not really for
having a calm state of mind,
it’s like a side effect and you will become
calm and you will be
happy, but to be honest, this is not the main
goal, shanti divan yuge said you become
attached to small pleasures
in small meditation, but you do not
achieve great pleasure, and this is what it means to
kill death. If I don’t like
meditating, what should I do? My
teacher said it’s easy, observe how people
around you are, then we will have an
interest in meditation, this is a difficult answer,
but meditation is not always
fun, it’s not always fun, exercises are not
always the most pleasant, but we need them.  You need to
do this, so be serious,
stern, breathe correctly and you will not have the
main pain. Why meditate is
to kill death, me, joy, there is no
other choice. The next question is
whoever has the microphone chooses.
Collect a good question and Petya, don't
forget to drink sour. I want to ask you
about the process of this meditation. During the
process, when you led us, I
felt some kind of sadness. I don't know
why. Let me explain
a little. The process itself has two parts and the
lion dance meditation.
Who taught this meditation?
We have this meditation in the book, because
Sangi is very famous. Why do we do this?
This meditation, the dance, and it has two
parts. The first part has, like, 8
meditations, not counting the air conditioner. After
the air conditioners, we
observe the heartbeat, then we move
inside the heart, then we move well, the tariff to the
center of the heart,
then inside the sugar crystal, then into
the ocean, then into the sky. We stop the mind,
block thoughts and leaving it. We stop
intelligently, leave it at rest. We don't try to
slow down anything. These are 8 preparatory
steps. If you count with the air conditioner, there will
be 9. Something funny. Who taught
this Maitriya meditation? He taught this
meditation, and Sangi to the head, and Sangi.  and
then asanga taught us this in this world,
these first eight or nine levels of
these meditations are not meditation, they are
just a warm-up when you perform them
at the Olympic Games, run, for example,
at first you need to stretch
your body for one hour to prepare, if you try to
run without warming up,
you will harm yourself in meditation,
his dance in Sanskrit, in Sanskrit
the name is sitkha with jim bita, it
means dance, these first eight
steps and
this is not meditation yet, do not do them as
meditation, I do not want to listen to hear that
you sat in meditation and stopped your mind
for 1 hour, this will not help you
to stretch, warm up your mind, 2 years
if you participate in the Olympic Games and
run, and all other countries are also
handfuls and you are still warming up, but you still run,
you warm up, you will not
win a gold medal for a gold medal for
warming up, so there are two parts of
this meditation, these first eight
steps are just to stretch our mind,
so please do not do a warm-
up for two hours, it is just a warm-up  and
preparation is not yet meditation when
meditation begins when your teacher
comes this is real meditation and then
you go into a past life and so two
parts and think about it this way the
window was just necessary sadness is felt I
think that this is important if you are sad
focus more on the good
qualities of the teacher what makes you
happy what from what you feel
inspired how and what beautiful things
which beautiful quality you see the
teacher himself then it will be cool to go into a
past life those good qualities
that you see in himself teaches does it come
from you just like a pen
[music]
every time you see something
beautiful in your life it comes from
you you see a very wise teacher you
see very good people you see
beautiful people they all come from you
and you need to rejoice you do not need to be
sad you cannot see beauty
if you yourself are ugly
maitre did not create this meditation think
about the most evil person you
know the most angry and then go to
your past life and think about
how angry and angry you were in a
past life this is not this meditation
our think about the best person
you know the person with the most
beautiful kind heart it comes
from you then think about your past life
what you did
to create such a person in this
meditation you need to think only about beauty
beautiful kind things and then you
will not be sad
good one more question I meditated for
about 2 years and if I do 10 15 minutes and it's
okay if I do longer
sessions such as dancing its
45 minutes 1 hour then time processes I
feel like I'm losing my
mind I can't remember what happened and
sociable memory or I'm losing
knowledge why is this and besides a
healthier diet and drinking less alcohol
what else can be done a good question
there is a very famous teaching about
meditation
of course your body and the people you
meet comes from you it's easy
if you come across the words person it
means in the past we were evil person
I have a friend there is such a famous
English phrase I am surrounded by
idiots when he says so yes it's
true it's true why quipu people
around you is a mirror of yourself good
people will only kind people people
will hear only sufferers people idiots
will be surrounded by people diodes  What we
see is a reflection in the mirror,
even the weather or the progress of the road, all
this comes from us. I worked for 19 years in
New York. Some days the traffic jams were
just terrible. I was an hour late for
work. I left the house at the same
time as my friend. We live in the same
city and my friend arrived at work
earlier,
but I was often late for work.
Even traffic jams from Africa, everyone has their own traffic
jams. I'm
telling you about this. What you hear
inside yours and also comes from you
and the facts about
reflection are important. Your own if you are
very busy.
It comes from what you did
last week. It comes from your
behavior last week. Your
own thoughts and actually from yourself.
People older than me should I sit on a soft
seat or on a hard one. Not hold your
hands like this or hold your hands like this.
Close my eyes or
open them slightly. The answer doesn't matter. It doesn't
matter. I have a friend who always
meditates lying on the floor on the bed and
he has an excellent slow night. I'm not
telling you that you need to do this in the entrance, but
for the sake of example, and yourself, what are these special 7 and
in order to have a good meditation, I walked with
the action from  I can
focus on meditation. I did the whole dance. At
some point, it starts to wander.
I'm losing 15 minutes here. I've
completely lost meditation. This is happening.
What did you do in
relation to other people last
week? If you want to have a good
meditation next week,
sow the seeds today. When you have a
good meditation next week, and
if you want to have a pen next week,
share the pen with other
people today. The seed needs time to
germinate,
and also inside the
seed, it takes time for the bust and ships to
talk.  It's true, the real secret of
meditation is always asking me, people, "
Eat la beaute" from you. No
teacher has ever told you. You always
need to raise your left leg first, and then think about
it. One hour, he told me, I tried it, you
need your left leg first,
and then your right. They say that if you put your
right leg first, and then Lego, there will always be
meditation. It doesn't
matter. You sow your meditation.
Last week, the seeds were sown.
The wife in bed. The wife in the kitchen sowed the
hum of a stupid husband. Last week, she
yelled at her children. Last week, they
sowed
the meditation that you had today.
Last week, a slow answer to your
question about our
tea. Special thanks, I personally work. 1
answer. Actually, don't disturb the
minds of other people. This
week, it's like yelling at your children.
If you started at your children this
week, then next week, there's a
reason your husband yells at you seven times.
If you talk about things that
upset other people, this week,
next week, she puts it down. When
you close your eyes,
you will lose meditation. You understand, we are
meditation.  It comes from you, just like a
pen, just like a
husband, you need to sow
good seeds for meditation in the kitchen.
This week, be careful and watch what
you say to other people.
My teacher said
never lie, never told a lie. I am
Mario, a teacher. I have a special question.
If my mother
buys dresses in a store alone and she is
very ugly. Made of fire, the colors are not ugly. The
shape is ugly. She comes
home in
January-May. What do you think about
my new dress?
I say, well, get dressed. She goes and
changes clothes
as you like. I ask, don't you need to
say the truth or not. No, mom doesn't need to
say that. Such a beautiful dress.
You see, be careful not to
upset
other people. If I tell my mother, her
face is ugly, the shape is also ugly. It will
hurt her. Then next
week, my meditation will be over. I will lose my
meditation
because I disturbed my mother with my muse. Mom
is the biggest karmic
object. Mom and Dad. I disturb my
mother. Then next week, my
meditation will be over. The teacher didn't actually
say, don't lie directly. And in the end, you can
say about the price. It's so good.  dress,
so make mom happy, good
to them, for this time,
when you sow the seeds, good
meditations, years, my flight tomorrow, we
will continue to answer questions about
meditation.